Hey besties, if you were given $15
billion, what could you build? The next
PayPal, perhaps the next SpaceX, the
next Google, or would you build a
high-speed rail?
>> This is the California highspeed rail
that goes to absolutely nowhere. And I
mean absolutely nowhere, I mean
literally nowhere.
This is all California has to show for
$15 billion in 18 years of work. In
2008, they said they were going to
connect Los Angeles to San Francisco. To
this date, they have connected literally
nothing. And now to finish this project,
they're estimated it's going to cost a
hundred to $200 billion. And funny
enough, in 2008, China also created
their own highspeed rail. And they've
connected the whole entire country of
China, over 30,000 miles. here in
California. They haven't connected a
single town. We're going to be breaking
down this entire thing from start to
finish to show you guys what is actually
happening with the California highspeed
rail. Let's get into it. Now, let's go
talk to somebody who knows a lot about
the California highspeed rail. What's
the truth about the highspeed rail here
inside of California? Uh, well, we call
it California highspeed rail, but all we
have is concrete and rebar and about $15
billion spent. It currently is right now
the most expensive infrastructure
project happening in the world today.
The original estimates for California
highspeed rail was $33 billion.
It then jumped to $126 billion and now
the newest estimate is $236 billion.
This project is on track for one thing
and that is to be the third most
expensive infrastructure project in the
history of the world. Number one is the
interstate project of the 1950s. Number
two is the International Space Station
and now it is California highspeed rail.
The difference between those three
projects is you can drive on I5 or you
can go on I80 and drive across the
entire country. You can go to outer
space. We will never ride California
highspeed rail.
>> So it goes from there all the way to
right here. This is where it ends. It is
probably the most expensive piece of
concrete uh known to man and often
referred to here in the Central Valley
as a modern-day Stonehenge.
>> How come they continue to say that
they're going to continue to build the
highspeed rail when there's actually
proof that it is quite literally
impossible?
>> Governor Nuomo in a in a video himself
from 2016, I believe, actually admitted
to all of us in a private video that he
doesn't believe that this project will
ever be done in our lifetime. He said
that
>> okay the facts seem overwhelming that
this project is not going to materialize
in our lifetime
>> and now this is a result of over $15
billion.
Who's taken the $15 billion? And where's
the $15 billion gone if this is all that
they have to show for
>> onethird of the entire cost of
California highspeed rail has gone to
this part called change order delays uh
because they didn't know where the
infrastructure was and or how to build
this actual train contractors that got
awarded a a parcel to work on are owed
$170,000 a day, $5 million a month for
every single day they can't work. We
just settled here in California very
recently in February uh the largest
settlement in a delay settlement for
over half a billion dollars. Because a
contractor couldn't work on the actual
project, they were owed a half a billion
dollars.
>> What are some of the biggest examples of
waste, fraud, and just complete
incompetence by the government when you
see this highspeed rail? California was
supposed to buy the actual trains and
the trains that would be considered
highspeed rail. The state didn't buy the
trains,
my opinion, because they know that there
will never be a train on these tracks.
>> So, California has not even bought the
trains yet.
>> No. If we would just buy one-way tickets
at current ridership between San
Francisco and LA, which is the goal of
California highspeed rail, we could
subsidize free tickets one way for the
next 150 years.
Now, with the new estimate that
California highspeed rail is going to be
$236 billion,
uh, we could subsidize one-way tickets
between San Francisco and LA for the
next 300 years. So, to me, it would make
more sense for all of us to just buy the
flights from San Francisco to LA than it
would be to build a train or whatever
this is and spend more money doing that.
I mean, it doesn't make any sense
mathematically.
>> Now, we're on top of the highspeed rail,
and there's not any rail that has been
placed. It's actually just a bunch of
cement. The highspeed rail to nowhere.
That's what they should call it,
actually. And despite the California
highspeed rail appearing to be
impossible to finish, California has
allocated $1 billion a year to finish
the project, while they actually need
anywhere from 100 to $200 billion to
finish it. And the high-speed rail even
becomes more interesting and you realize
how impossible it is the further along
the alignment you go. And later we'll be
confronting the center who's over the
oversight committee for the
transportation inside of California. We
then saw some train tracks where the hub
of the highspeed rail is supposed to be.
Hello.
>> Hey.
>> How you guys doing? Is this the
highspeed rail though?
>> Uh no. So you can't be out. This is
high.
>> Not the highspeed rail. Where's the
going to be the hub for the highspeed
rail?
>> I'm not sure.
>> You don't know where the hub is going to
be for the highspeed rail?
No. All right. And despite these guys
saying this is not the hub for the
highspeed rail, which it really is, we
then went down the alignment and this is
what we found. So, this location right
here was actually bought in 2006 for
developers to develop this land. And
then they set forth the plan to actually
go through with the highspeed rail in
2008. In order for the highspeed rail to
actually happen, they're going to have
to go through and buy each and every
single one of these houses that is
currently being built. Keep in mind
right now they're building the highspeed
rail while these people are building
houses on the alignment. Let's go talk
to a city manager right now. And how is
it possible right now that here in
California you have a government who is
spending billions upon billions of
dollars for this highspeed rail.
Meanwhile, a construction site is right
here where they're building houses on
where that highspeed rail is supposed to
go. Uh
>> we don't really know. Typically
government buys all of the alignment up
front. That way you don't have cost of
buying it once it's developed. Like this
will bring it up 10 or 11 times. what
bare land value would be. So, we don't
really know. They we communication is
pretty sparse, so we're left mostly in
the dark.
>> Do you think that this highspeed rail
has just been some sort of fantasy for
the people inside of Sacramento and the
politicians of California?
>> Look, it it's you've got a project that
duplicates Amtrak's current service
route. I will tell you from a ground
perspective, we don't understand why
they're sticking two rail lines next to
each other that are going to serve the
same areas. And how many more cases of
this do you think are inside of this
alignment for the highspeed rail?
>> I don't think this is atypical. I think
this has happened quite a bit up and
down the valley.
>> California actually abandoned the route
from San Francisco to Los Angeles. Now
they're focusing from Merced to
Bakersfield. And so the highspeed rail
will actually not even be servicing
people from Los Angeles to San
Francisco. The highspeed rail bridge
ends over there. It continues over here
onto this road, but as you'll see, it
then has to go through a bunch of
farmland just like this. Now, they have
the road right here for the highspeed
rail, but in other locations, do they
have it? We're going to go speak with
the farmer right now. Now, we're in the
middle of an orchard right now. How will
the farmers be affected from the
highspeed rail?
>> Ranches that have been contiguous for
hundreds of years will now be split. And
that requires you now having to travel
to both sides, right? your
infrastructure have to be pulled from
one side to the other whether it be
irrigation, power supplies, and even
just and operationally it's just going
to make it everything real inconvenient.
>> When California brought about the plan
for the highspeed rail, did you guys
vote on it or did you guys have any say
so with it or do you even think it's
going to happen?
>> You know, all the voters had a ch had a
chance to vote and it passed. Um but it
was a very vague on the ballot. No one
knew where it was going to go. To me,
they're putting in all the wrong spots.
Um, it was to serve two different
populations in the north, the state and
the south. And they're where they're
deciding to put it is it's going to
impact an area that didn't need the
highspeed rail to begin with.
>> They're allocating millions and billions
of dollars to this each and every single
year. And now they're saying they're
going to need uh almost hundred billion
dollars more, if not $200 billion. What
could farmers of California do if they
had hundred billion invested into them?
>> Oh man, it could revolutionize the
state. I mean, agriculture has been the
backbone of this state since its
founding. And we're not investing in
water infrastructure. We're not
investing in energy infrastructure. And
it's just it's it's sad cuz we're
worried about a train that's going to
serve a small sector of the population.
And what really needs to be done is
something that's going to be good for
all of us in the state.
>> So pretty soon we could see a high-speed
rail come right through here where all
these almonds are at. And people are
going to be suffering because of it.
>> Yes. And there'll probably be no one on
the train. Now, we came here to
Sacramento to go speak with the people
at the California Highspeed Rail
Authority office. It is 4:09 right now,
and we just went inside and nobody's
here. Hallelujah.
>> Really?
>> Said they're open.
>> They close at 5:00 p.m. However, they
are not here. But we are going to go
speak with a senator who just approved
and passed a bill that's going to give
$1 billion for the next 20 years to the
California Highspeed Rail Authority.
We're going to go talk to him and see
why he approved that. Senator Cortezi,
how are you doing? Good. My name is Nick
Shirley. We're doing a a little
investigation on the highspeed rail. We
just want to ask what made you want to
secure $1 billion for the next 20 years
for the highspeed rail.
>> I believe it's a good uh long-term
commitment that we need to make.
>> And do you think that's actually ever
going to happen here inside the state of
California?
>> It is happening. Have you been there?
>> Yeah, I actually have.
>> All right. Well, then you know it's
happening.
>> And there's actually not a single piece
of rail or track that's been laid.
>> They're getting ready to do that right
now.
And do you think in 20 years the
highspeed rail will be done as promised
is going to be done in 2020? It
>> might be, might not.
>> Gavin Newsome even said in a private
video like it's not even possible
essentially.
>> I have a lot of transportation projects
I've worked on for 20 years that are
just finally getting started and they're
all worth it.
>> And do you believe as a chair of the
Senate Transportation Committee, do you
believe the highspeed rail authority has
been sufficiently accountable for the
increase and delays that have taken
place with the highspeed rail?
>> Well, we're trying to hold them
accountable. And what can you give to
people to make them believe that the
highspeed rail is actually going to be
built and finished in our lifetime or in
your lifetime?
>> It's not my commitment. My commitment is
it's the greatest economic development
project in the country and uh people
should be embracing that all the way to
the federal government. There's no other
economic development project that even
comes close to that in this country. And
it's a shame that uh you know certain
people in the country aren't taking
taking that seriously. So, uh, that's
how we get things done is when the
federal government, the state government
work together. Build dams, build
bridges, build highways, build highspeed
rail. That's what needs to happen.
>> And you do believe that we'll see the uh
finish of the highspeed rail in our
lifetime.
>> There's 21 construction projects going
on right now with thousands of workers.
So, you'll see it get done.
>> Besties, don't be like the highspeed
rail.
>> Please welcome Mick Shirley.
[__] yeah. [__] yeah. What's up, bro?
Hey, man.
>> Saxs, this is your guy. Get in there.
>> Wow. Uh maybe a good place to start
actually is that California was so
afraid of what you're doing, exposing
their fraud, that they actually passed a
law to stop you from doing your
investigations and you know your videos
where you actually show up at these
places that are stealing taxpayer money.
I could you just I mean I I'm still like
shocked that they could get away with
that. I know you're fighting it in court
and I fully expect it'll be
unconstitutional in like 20 years
whenever it makes its way through the
court system, but could you just explain
that?
>> Yes. So, I exposed California for all
the fraud that they've enabled here
inside the state. And they use what's
called immigration support service
providers, and it quite literally means
anybody who provides services to illegal
immigrants or immigrants. And that
includes nonprofits and healthcare
facilities. So, uh actually today, this
just happened literally today. I filmed
all these daycarees in San Diego and
when I exposed it, Newsome came after
me. But today, they found 12 individuals
who were all immigrants and they charged
them of $10 million of fraud. That
happened today.
>> California did.
>> California,
that DOJ did.
So, underneath this new bill, this new
law that they created, if these
immigration support service providers
were to give me a piece of paper saying,
"Hey, you can't upload that video. I
can't upload that video." And they only
created that after I exposed the fraud.
>> Wait, wait, wait. Okay, let me First of
all, what is an was it immigration
support services like what is that?
>> Yeah, it means legal services, healthc
care facilities, um quite literally
anything where your tax dollars go to
provide the services for illegal
immigrants or immigrants here in San
>> from the state of California. So the
state of California is funding
>> these businesses basically.
>> Yes.
>> To provide services to illegals.
>> Yeah. It can be medical. It can even be
NOS's, nonprofits that received grants
from the government. For instance, the
people who sponsored this bill is called
Chura. They've received $80 million and
they do the advocacy work for illegal
immigrants here inside the United
States.
>> Wait, they got $80 million. Sorry,
million or billion. 80 million million
nonprofit.
>> Nonprofit.
>> And then it sounds like they're the law
is written that any service to
immigrants
>> Yeah. you can't go do this work because
they're trying to protect the community.
>> So, wait, but how do they stop you? So,
let's say you so you go to one of these
NOS's or businesses that's received this
funding. You record it. Um, and now
they're saying you can't upload it.
>> Yeah. So, if they simply were enrolled
in this service, then they give me a
piece of paper saying, "Hey, you can't
upload that video, a demand letter. I
can't upload the video." And if I do,
I'll get a $4,000 fine. And then I'll
have to go to court and I'll have to pay
for their legal fees if they win. So
$4,000 is just the minimum if they have
10 employees in there who all are part
of the service.
>> Sorry, doesn't that violate your
constitutional rights?
>> Yeah, first amendment rights.
>> And so do you sue the state of
California?
>> Yeah, I'm suing the state of California
right now
>> to undo that bill.
>> Yes.
>> Obstensively, by the way, Saxs, this was
all under the pretext of our favorite
term, safety, because what Nick Shirley
was doing in knocking on a door and
saying, "Is this business open or
closed?" was making people feel unsafe.
And if you use that word unsafe, well
then everybody has to rally around it.
And they literally called this the Nick
Shirley law. So I think this is the most
amazing uh badge for you. And it's an
award. The fact that they're creating
laws to try to stop you from doing basic
journalism means you're kicking [__]
ass, Nick. Don't stop.
>> Um
these First Amendment cases though have
been incredibly well litigated. So, do
they just pass this knowing that it will
probably get overturned at the federal
level and then it's up to you to raise
the money, find the conlaw people, and
then take the case? Is that what it is?
Or do they actually legitimately think
there's legal standing? Like, what does
your team tell you about that law that's
trying to stop you?
>> Yeah. I don't think they thought Nick
Shirley would hear about this bill cuz
they called it AB2624.
And unless an assemblyman dubbed it the
Stop Nick Shirley Act, I probably
wouldn't have heard about it. So
California, they've pretty much passed
all these laws. Like it's it's called
comeie for you. Call me Foria for a
reason. Like to forget a bill passed in
California in the in the legislators.
There's 40 senators. 30 of them are
Democrats. 10 of them are Republicans.
It needs 21 votes to pass. So it's quite
literally nearly almost impossible for a
Republican to pass anything here inside
the state of California.
>> Let's be clear, Gavin Newsome signed
this.
>> Yeah.
>> And who is the impetus of this bill?
Like is there a way that people are
teasing out the the funding cycle and
the people that were behind this thing
or no?
>> Well, Chura, they're the co-sponsor but
who received $80 million. The person who
created this bill is the wife of the
attorney general. Her name is Mia Bont.
So, meanwhile, the attorney general is
supposed to prosecute the fraud. Well,
his wife's creating laws to make it
harder for fraud to be prosecuted and to
go after and be exposed.
>> How did you start? Let's take a step
back, Nick, for the folks that don't
necessarily know the origin story. How
did you stumble into this? because yeah
it's uh when I was 15 years old I
started making YouTube videos vlogs and
pranks as I got older I got more
interested to see what was actually
happening in the world but at that time
around 2020 you couldn't make videos
with the word Trump in the title or if
you talked about politics or talked
about co you might be demonetized so you
couldn't make any money and so then I
ended up taking like a 2-year break on a
mission trip for our church and went to
uh Santiago Chile I started learning
about um all these people that were
fleeing Venezuela they were going to
Chile and they were telling me about how
people are going to the United States so
then I got back to the United States, my
mom was also keeping up to date with
that. And then when I got to the back
home, I went to the southern border and
I started interviewing people in Spanish
saying like, "How'd you guys come over
here? Like, what's going on?" And I
thought it was like super sad that the
all these people were coming over
fleeing the country. And then I get this
lady's WhatsApp who was from Ecuador.
She said she had no money at the border.
And the next day she texted me saying
she was in New York City. And I was
like, "That's super strange." And so for
the past 2 and a half years, I've been
making a video every single week about
something that's happening here inside
the United States. And like I went from
20,000 subscribers, nobody knowing me to
now having I created one of the most
viewed videos ever in internet history
exposing the fraudsters in Minnesota.
And uh I was I only knew about that
fraud because I had been making a video
every single week from across the world.
>> What happens like whistleblowers reach
out to you and say, "Hey, Nick, go over
here. Go over there."
>> Yes. So, like I rely heavily upon the
people in in these states to let me know
what's going on. Like I'm pretty much
like a I said made a joke. I'm I'm like
a congressman for the entire United
States who actually listens to the
people.
>> But I don't work for anybody.
>> Well, and what I really appreciate about
what you're doing is Man on the Street
is a really challenging uh art form and
journalistic uh format. It's incredibly
brave for you to go out there, put
yourself at risk, and you have, just to
be clear, so people can appreciate this,
you have no formal journalistic
training. You have learned everything on
your own, and you have funded it. Uh,
and I think it's important that we're
clear about this because people make
allegations, oh, you're a plant.
Somebody's funding you. You're funded by
the people through your X.com account.
You make tens of thousands of dollars a
month, I think, maybe hundreds of
thousands a year just to sustain
yourself.
>> Yeah. for me to like when I my whole
goal was to make $300 a day in 2023. I
thought I could like do everything with
$300 a day. I was like, I'm going to be
balling. That'sund that's a $100,000 a
year. And then uh I started making more
and more money. I post this Minnesota
fraud video. My mom literally films it.
That's my favorite thing. People like
Nick's a Fed. I'm like, would a Fed have
his mom filming his YouTube videos when
he's 24 years old?
>> Not a fed thing to do.
>> Yeah. Not a Fed thing to do. I think
they could find somebody better if they
if that was the case. But um I was just
100% working uh for myself to show
people what was actually happening and
I've created a lot of change.
>> The the audience reaction is a little
polarized, right? There are obviously
people like us who are like,
>> you know, stealing is wrong.
>> Um then there's obviously fraudsters who
can be angry at you,
>> very angry.
>> Um but then there are passive viewers
that actually really dislike what you're
doing.
>> Yeah. I don't understand.
>> How do you unpack that? Like why why is
that reaction happening? Ultimately, I
know what I'm Ultimately, I know what
I'm doing is right. And for you to be
defending a a fraudster who opens up a
layering center, I'm like, you might
need to rethink something.
>> I can tell you what this is.
>> People say you're racist.
>> I can tell you what's happening here,
Shimoth.
>> Having been a journalist and come up
with these people.
>> Oh, here we go.
>> No, no, it's actually super important.
>> Jason lectures Nick.
>> It's not a lecture. It's an insight. Um,
and you're lucky to hear it. Uh, so sit
back. uh what you represent to them is a
threat because they came up and they
wanted to do what you're doing. They
were idealistic, these journalists, and
they wanted to be brave enough to
uncover these things and they've become
captured and politicized and they have
picked a side. You haven't.
>> That's why they that's why they
criticize you. And the criticism they
have of you is, "Oh, he didn't he wasn't
facteing here. Wasn't thorough enough
here." Yeah. Okay, fine. on the margins,
you're learning on the job. And I've had
conversations with you privately about
little nuances of things that you need
to tighten up. None of that is
important. What's important is that you
find fraud. You find actual real fraud
and you put the people on camera and you
[__] shame them and then they get
arrested and you're forcing the AGs in
this country to face it. And it's just
you. It's just you and your pure desire
and energy to do it. And that's what
journalists hate about you because they
could do it too. And they should be
ashamed that they don't. This was the
job of 60 Minutes and Front Line and
they forgot how to do their job. And
you're picking up the mantle of what
Front Line and 60 Minutes used to be.
>> I agree. Give me some.
>> [__] yeah.
>> I die.
>> Are the AG's taking up the cases?
>> Well, I mean, I'll go expose it and if
they want to do something about it, I
put all the information in the videos.
And so that's one thing I have seen is
there actually has been change like they
just found the 12 people today uh the
leers in Minnesota most most of them
fled the country I believe but they got
the head.
>> Oh is that right? So give us the kota
actually about the the daycarees in
Minnesota.
>> Yes. So the daycarees in Minnesota they
the was the craziest thing because I was
just sitting in my room. I just posted
that video. I had no idea it was going
to be like the biggest video ever. It
got 4 billion views in 7 days.
>> Uh which was pretty insane. Uh so I post
that video and then there starts to be
like riots in protest. People start
dying to cover for the L the leers. Uh
the the politicians were like
incentivizing people to go out and riot
because they knew like the ICE was there
but they could distract everyone by
getting people out to the street to
cover up for the fraud. Well, it didn't
really work cuz Tim Waltz dropped out of
re-election.
In Minnesota, they the head person of
the Laring centers who had received $4
million, she tried to go to London on a
one-way ticket and then she got caught
for daycare fraud and so she was the
head like the head honcho of the
lessers. She got caught. She got busted.
Um then the biggest autism bust of all
time took place there as well. So like
I've been very productive.
>> So wait, so did she get prosecuted?
>> Yes. And she plead guilty.
>> She plead guilty.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh wow. And what's the sentence? Uh, I
don't know yet.
>> Okay. Maybe it hasn't happened yet or
>> Yeah.
>> Did you Did you see Bill Gurley's
presentation?
>> I watched a bit of it. It's kind of hard
to hear back.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, there's a point he was
making, which is that journalists seem
to have become selective in the stories
that they're chasing and the
investigations that they're doing and
there seems to be a reason that's this
kind of politicized point. What's your
view? Have you met with journalists and
talked with them? Have any of them
reached out? And do you have a sense on
what what what goes on? what motivates
them to say things, do things one way or
not the other way.
>> No one from the mainstream has reached
out to me to say like, "Hey, how are you
doing this?" Instead, they like
investigate me and they'll write hit
pieces on me. I'm like, "Okay, like good
for you."
>> Investigating the investigator. Yeah.
That's that that shows you exactly how
threatened they are by you. And I think
where where you are going to be just
having known you for one year and
watching the improvements in the
crispness, you are going to be so
dangerous when you have a modest amount
of resources. And I think what we really
need to do is commit to making sure you
have more funding. And so I I'm going to
right after we get on here, I'm going to
subscribe and I'm going to put in, you
know, whatever a couple thousand dollars
a month to support you. And I think
everybody here should. You're doing
great work. You need to have some
researchers on the team. You need to
have some backup and you need to have
security because what you're doing is
truly a threat to criminals and the mob
has always wanted.
>> No, I'll take it.
>> What was that? What was it?
>> You were the son that Jason has always
wanted.
>> No, no. I mean, I have three great
daughters, but I I'm just you're what I
got in when I got into journalism. What
you're doing is why I got into it, which
was the role of journalism. And I think
Bill Gurley pointed it out so well in
his talk, which was there are still
great investigative journalists out
there. There just not enough of them.
And I I think it's fantastic that
there's a new generation doing this and
that you're doing is
>> Yeah, this is what So there have been a
few others that have emerged since you
came out. Minnesota piece was such a big
maybe inspiration, but it was also a
beacon to a lot of people like, oh, we
can go do this like you did. Are you
seeing more of this? Do you think that
they're being successful? And what do
you think's changing?
>> Yeah, I think a lot of people are taking
it up and they're seeing like with X,
like if it wasn't for Elon and X, like
none of this would have been possible.
For instance, I post that video about
the fraud in on YouTube. It does well.
It gets a few million views on X. It got
140 million views. And the most
important people in the world see it and
they're able to see like, oh, we're not
doing our job. Let's go do what needs to
be done. Like the government, I caught
them kind of backhanded um on that. So,
they had to go step in. But I do think a
lot of individuals like I do hope I am
motivating a lot of kids, especially my
generation, to be less of a complainer
and be more of a doer.
So I and I think journalism people think
of it as just like showing what's going
on. Well, you can actually have massive
create massive change inside of the
country in the areas that you live in.
Uh that's something that I've seen with
my journalism. I'm like I'm not just
playing like the defense. Like I'm
actually going out showing people what's
going on and I'm not just leaving the
story after it's done. Like I'm
continuing to follow through because if
it's real corruption like it needs to be
taken down,
>> right? And what other people don't
realize uh because you became I think
pretty famous from the Minnesota video,
but you had other stuff before where it
wasn't about chasing down corruption
like you went into the FAS and Brazil,
right? Which was incredibly scary
>> and you've done a lot of this stuff. Are
you still doing those sorts of things or
is everything now about government
corruption?
>> I would love to continue to do those
videos and I will do more these past 8
months. Uh every morning I'm waking up
to something new about fraud and
corruption. So I've kind of just like
been spearheading that. But uh I would
like to get more into that stuff. Like I
I like I I almost got kidnapped in the
Brazilian fabllas. I met up with this
the head of Commando Vermelo inside this
in inside this FLLA in Rio de Janeiro.
And literally like there's only a few
things that could have happened with me
and him and this broken down shackle in
the top of the FLLA got also nearly
taken hostage in Cuba. Two car a two
star communist general came down to try
and figure out why I was in Cuba and why
I was leaving early. So like that
stuff's still super important. I the
fraud stuff's just kind of taken over my
life recently though.
>> What are the other big pockets of fraud
that you are
scratching at that you think exist? The
big honeypotss that you're going to go
chase down and uncover.
>> I like welfare fraud here inside the
United States is just absolutely welfare
insane. Like all of it. Uh
>> can you explain that?
>> For instance, like food stamps. Uh
there's a there's a strip club in
Portland, Oregon where you can use your
SNAP card.
uh like the government especially
underneath Biden uh they literally let
open like the floodgates to fraud. I
mean Tim Waltz was celebrating and using
the daycarees in his debates against JD
Vance
>> right?
>> Uh so all these social benefit programs
have literally been looted whether it be
SNAP whether it be daycarees whether it
be adult daycarees like literally you
name it hospices like all these things
that have received government money are
just full of fraud. And so now you're
just trying to pull the thread and
uncover as much of it as possible.
>> Yeah. And it's hard now cuz like I have
to have security. Like people literally
want to kill me. And so I have to be
super strategic and like what's going to
stop a fraudster from me knocking on his
door and then he him realizing that his
time's up and him just shooting me so
the video doesn't get posted. Like
that's like stuff I think about when I
go to bed. Like how do I go out and make
these videos a bit differently?
>> Well, are there different ways that you
can get the information you need to tell
the story without actually having to
confront the person in real time? Yeah,
people want to see the person get
confronted.
>> So, I mean, but this is what's so
interesting because what you're talking
about is like at the end of the day,
you're still fighting the attention
mechanism that you live under, you know,
like your incentive is to tell the truth
and then but there's a last point where
your incentive is I must do something
that will get views as well.
>> Yeah. Like that's how all this stuff
happens. Well, you know, here I'm going
to
>> that's part of
>> 60 Minutes as an example does undercover
reporting and always has and they would
if a subject would not come on 60
Minutes, they would go to their home and
wait for them outside their office and
home to confront them and ask those
questions. They would tell them they're
going to do it. So, I think you're well
within your right to do that. I think as
you professionalize your operation, um,
and it's incredibly brave what you're
doing, I think you have to ask for a bit
more support from the audience. And I,
you know, right now you can do a $5
subscription, but you should also ask
people to be charter supporters, you
know, at a $500 level, $1,000 level like
Substack might allow you to do. And I
think you should be very aggressive in
asking for more support because the
government, we heard from Vice President
J. D. Vance, 10 20% of our tax dollars
are being wasted. If we support you to
do this work, get a researcher, get an
extra video editor. You just need about
three or four people around you to
support you. and this is really going to
take off. If you have those three or
four people, um, we're all going to save
more money. A and we need to as a
country to get behind you and say people
who are stealing from the government,
that is they should carry double the
sentence because you're stealing from
the actual society,
>> right? And I don't care what country, it
doesn't matter what state it is,
immigrant or American, and they've been
here. You're stealing from the actual
country that is giving you, you know,
the protection of living in these United
States. It is really sinister to steal
from the country. It really is. And and
just I'm I'm really upset that you are
faced with security issues and and a
lack of support and this criticism on
the ticky tacky things. Do not stop
doing what you're doing.
>> Thank you very much. And like if we can
stop fraud, we can literally save the
country. Like that's something people
don't understand. What what's crazy is
it's not just fraud. I think the
California highspeed rail project.
Anyone can look at that objectively and
say that is the most insane thing on
earth. Why are we doing this? $240
billion to go from Fresno to Modesto at
three times the price of an airplane
ticket. None of it makes sense.
Literally, it's like lit none of it
makes sense. And the guy got paid half a
billion for nonwork.
>> It's a billionaire in Italy who got paid
that money. I tricked him.
>> How much did he get paid?
>> Half a billion. So the
>> Say half a billion.
>> Did you watch the video?
>> Yeah. So after I saw that video, so Nick
Nick sent me that video and then I
traced down who got paid that half
billion and the ultimate owner is a
billionaire in Italy.
>> I didn't know that.
>> And um the whole story when you when you
kind of dig into this so this isn't
fraud. It's legal.
>> Mhm.
>> It's a legal system. It's a legal It's a
legal system and and I think it falls
under that idea of waste or some sort of
corruption, but I think it is as re the
fraud stuff anyone can get behind. But
this is the stuff
>> unethical and logical.
>> There's there's complacency, there's
corruption, there's unaccountability and
these are the things that just trickled
into this massive waterfall that we're
drowning in right now and I think it's
really important what you're doing and I
think on behalf of a lot of people I
really appreciate the mission you're on.
You're an incredible person. We thank
you for the work.
>> Thank you guys so much. Thanks for being
>> No problem. I appreciate it.
>> [__] yeah. Thanks,
>> brother. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you. Great job.
>> Thanks, Jason. Appreciate it.